<manpage>
<docdate>$Date: 2008/10/22 22:02:05 $</docdate>
<doctitle>MAKL-CONF</doctitle>
<os>UNIX</os>
<section>1</section>
<names>
    <name>makl-conf<desc>a wrapper around MaKL autoconfigure scripts.</desc></name>
</names>

<description> 
<name>makl-conf</name> is a wrapper around MaKL autoconfigure scripts.  A MaKL autoconfigure script is one using using the following basic framework: 
<literal>
                #!/bin/sh

                . "${MAKL_DIR}"/cf/makl.init

                makl_args_init "$@"

                makl_args_handle "$@"

                . "${MAKL_DIR}"/cf/makl.term
</literal>
When invoked, it searches the current working directory for a suitable config file name (see <name>FILES</name> section).  If found, the configure script is executed (the executable bit must be asserted for the user) with MAKL variables suitably set in its environment.
</description>

<usage>
    <arg>script-args<desc>Any argument exported by the autoconf script.</desc></arg>
</usage>

<examples>
Take a look at available options:
<literal>
    $ makl-conf --help
</literal>
Tell your autoconf script to use a different path for <name>DESTDIR:</name>
<literal>
    $ makl-conf --prefix=/another/prefix/path
</literal>
Tell MaKL that you want libraries to be built as shared objects and placed in a custom location:
<literal>
    $ makl-conf --enable_shared --dir-lib=/my/lib
</literal>
</examples>

<diagnostics>
    In case of error, <name>makl-conf</name> will bail out with non-zero exit code and appropriate diagnostic message on standard output.
</diagnostics>

<environment>
    The <name>makl-conf</name> command access the following environment variables, via <path>.maklrc</path> or <path>makl.conf</path> configuration files:
    <dl>
        <dd>MAKL_DIR</dd><dt>MaKL base dir which contains autoconf library functions.</dt>
        <dd>MAKL_CF_SCRIPTS</dd><dt>Used to extend the list of configuration script names.</dt>
    </dl>
</environment>

<files>
<file>configure, configure.sh, Configure, Configure.sh, config.sh, Config.sh<desc>File names which are scanned to find a match in the current working directory.</desc></file>
</files>

<seealso>
    <manpage>makl<section>1</section></manpage>
    <manpage>makl-new<section>1</section></manpage>
    <manpage>makl-tc<section>1</section></manpage>
</seealso>

<bugs>
    <p>If you catch a bug, please drop a note to makl-users@koanlogic.com.</p>
</bugs>

</manpage>
